

Portugal

+351 926 843 295

@ franciscoandre.farp@gmail.com

My Portfolio in ffarps.github.io

in My linkedin

## **OBJECTIVE**

My name is Francisco André Rodrigues Pereira, I'm 22 years old, from Mirandela, and I graduated from the Polytechnic Institute of Bragança with a degree in Informatics Engineering.

During the third year of the course and after completing it, I was awarded two research grants by the Centre for Research in Digitalisation and Intelligent Robotics (CeDRI).

Proactive and dedicated, ready to achieve great things.

## **EXPERIENCE**

#### Fev 2024-Present Full Stack Developer Intern at GoTVee

GoTVe

I contributed to the implementation of an AI virtual assistant, designed to interact with various documents and web pages, such as PDFs, CSVs, XMLs and Confluence. I supported the development of an API broker and engineered data to train language models. I optimised the code base with cross-functional teams. The assistant uses NLP and machine learning to answer questions about documents, increasing productivity and facilitating access to information.

#### Jul 2023-Sep 2023 Research Fellowship at CeDRI

CeDRI, Instituto Politécnico de Bragança

Contributed to an OpenZDM project related to developing a C# and OpenGl-based tool in Unity 3D, that aims to reduce defects in production chains in a car factory in the assembly and *body shop* zones.

#### Jul 2022-Jan 2023 Research Fellowship at CeDRI

CeDRI, Instituto Politécnico de Bragança

Worked on developing Augmented Reality (AR) and Virtual Reality (VR) apps in Unity, using different frameworks and tools, such as MRTK, ARCore, Vuforia SDK and ARFoundation.

# **EDUCATION**

#### Oct 2019-Jul 2023 Degree in Informatics Engineering

Instituto Politécnico de Bragança

Scientific Areas: Computer Science, Computer Engineering, Mathematics, Information Systems. Worked on many projects related to Web Development, Computer Architecture, Networking, 3D Modeling, Machine Learning, Data Structures, SQL and IoT.

2016-2019 High School Diploma

Agrupamento de Escolas de Mirandela

Science and technology

### LANGUAGES

#### HARD SKILLS

# SOFT SKILLS

Portuguese - native English - proficient German - rudimentary **Programming**: C#, Python, Java, JavaScript, TypeScript, etc

Source Control: Git, GitHub, GitLab, BitBucket

Linux and Bash Unity 3D

**Databases**: SQL and NoSQL

Self-taught Attention to detail Technical Writing Teamwork